Mahendra Thanniru

(+91) 9912933367 mahendra.thanniru777@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mah1ndra github.com/mah1ndra

Experienced Security Professional (4+ yr) skilled in vulnerability research and penetration testing with a strong passion for security-at-scale. Good at solving complex technology problems, and build tools to automate manual efforts.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

VMware India

Product Security Engineer

May 2021–Present

- Mitigated 10+ Critical vulnerabilities at the design phase through threat modeling across multiple products and helped in reducing the attack surface by 40% with a long-term threat mitigation plan.
- Through security code review reported 20+ critical and high severity vulnerabilities affecting multiple on-prem and SaaS products. Worked closely with the developer to provide defense in depth mitigation to future proof the product and limit the attacks blast radius.
- Found 15+ business logic vulnerabilities affecting multiple products through vulnerability research.
- Taken responsibility to eliminate more than 10+ bug classes across multiple products by enforcing secure default code patterns.
- Taken ownership of hardening CI/CD, Kubernetes environments with strict RBAC policies and security context for all product pipelines increasing supply chain security by 30%.
- Developed custom tools in python and golang as part of the automation initiative led by me to find dependency confusion and other common vulnerabilities code patterns.

ServiceNow India

Product Security Engineer

Feb 2021-May 2021

- Identified 1 critical deserialization vulnerability and 3 high severity vulnerabilities in the ServiceNow Core platform through Security code review. Worked closely with Dev to provide defense in depth security fixes.
- Delivered talk on common vulnerability and code patterns to educate developers as part of the security champion program.

OpenText India

Software Engineer

Oct 2019–Feb 2021

- Developed multiple features for OT healthcare SaaS and containerized its services to reduce down and increase performance by 30%
- Lead the infrastructure migration for critical patch delivery service which increased availability and security to 50%
- Lead for security code review for all services and conducted office hours on finding security vulnerabilities through code audit as part of developer education.

EDUCATION

BV Raju Institute of Technology

Hyderabad, India

Bachelor of Technology(concentration: Computer Science)

May 2020

PROFESSIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Certifications: OSCP, HCNA, CKAD
- Published CVE-2022-1553 for a critical Auth bypass in OSS and Contributed secure code to multiple OSS projects
- Submitted bugs to Paypal, Snapchat, Librepay, Upwork, Twitter through their bug bounty program.
- Documented Vulnerability research and critical Pentest finding in my **Blog**: https://mah1ndra.github.io/.
- Part of **Synack Red Team** Perform Red Team engagements on provided IP ranges and submit vulnerabilities.
- Awarded Elevate our best award at VMware for evaluating Log4j and patching multiple products through automation in a very short span and secured critical Federal and healthcare customers.